jotform.co 2019-12-25

# JotForm Privacy Policy | The JotForm Blog

**This privacy policy explains how JotForm Inc. handles your personal information and data. We value your trust, so we’ve strived to present this policy in a clear and; plain language. The policy is structured so you can quickly find answers to the questions that interest you the most.**

This privacy policy applies to all the products, services and websites offered by JotForm Inc. and their affiliates, except where otherwise noted. Products, services and websites are collectively referred to as the “services” in this policy. Some services have supplementary privacy statements that explain, in more detail, our specific privacy practices in relation to these services. Unless otherwise noted, all services are provided by JotForm Inc., which is based in the United States.

**IF YOU CREATE FORMS:**

**Your form data is owned by you.**  Additionally, JotForm Inc. treats your forms as if they were private, unless you made your forms publicly available via a public link. JotForm Inc. does not sell or make available your forms to anyone and does not use the form responses you collect for purposes unrelated to you or our services, except in a limited set of circumstances (e.g. JotForm Inc. is compelled by a subpoena, or if you’ve given us permission to do so).

**JotForm Inc. safeguards respondents’ email addresses.**  To make it easier for you to invite people to complete your forms via email, you may upload lists of email addresses, in which case JotForm Inc. acts as a mere custodian of that data. JotForm Inc. doesn’t sell or make available these email addresses and we use them only as directed by you and in accordance with this policy. The same is true for any email addresses collected through your forms.

**JotForm Inc. holds your data securely.**  Read our [Security Statement](https://www.jotform.com/security/) for more information.

**Form data is stored on servers located in the United States.  **More information is available if you are located in Europe. JotForm Inc. will process your form data on your behalf and under your instructions, including those agreed to in this privacy policy.

**IF YOU ANSWER FORMS:**

**Forms are administered by form creators.**  Form creators build tens of thousands of forms each day using our services. JotForm Inc. hosts the forms on our websites and collect the responses that you submit to the form creator. If you have any questions about a form you are taking, please contact the form creator directly as JotForm Inc. is not responsible for the content of that form or your responses to it. The form creator is generally the same person that invited you to complete the form and sometimes this individual, company or organization has its own privacy policy.

**Are your responses anonymous?**  This depends on how the form creator has configured the form. Contact this individual, company or organization to learn more.

**JotForm Inc. does not sell or make available**   **your responses to third parties.**  JotForm Inc. doesn’t sell or share your form responses with third party advertisers or marketers (although the form creator might, so we advise that you contact this individual, company or organization to learn more). JotForm Inc. merely acts as a custodian on behalf of the form creator who controls your data, except as further described in this privacy policy with regard to public forms.

If you think a form violates our [Terms of Use](https://www.jotform.com/help/8-Terms-of-Use) or may be engaging in illegal activity, [click here](https://www.jotform.com/answers/) to report it.

JotForm Inc. is used by form creators, people who create and conduct forms online, and form respondents, people who answer those forms. The information we receive from form creators and form respondents and how we handle it is separate, so this privacy policy is segmented into two parts :

  1. Privacy for Form Creators
  2. Privacy for Form Respondents

**PRIVACY FOR FORM CREATORS**

**What information does  JotForm Inc. collect?**

When you use JotForm Inc., we collect information relating to you and your use of our services from a variety of sources. These are listed below. The sections following describe how JotForm Inc. uses this information.

**Information we collect directly from you.**

**Registration information.**  You need to register for a JotForm Inc. account before you can create forms on JotForm Inc.. When you register for an account, we collect your username, password and email address.

**Billing information.**  If you make a payment to JotForm Inc., we require that you provide your billing details, including name, address, email address and financial information corresponding to your selected method of payment (e.g. a credit card number and expiration date or a bank account number). If you provide a billing address, we will regard that as the location of the account holder. Our integrations with 3rd party payment gateways are for processing only. JotForm Inc. does not store or log any sensitive cardholder data provided by you or your form users. JotForm Inc. follows industry standard best practices to protect security of cardholder data during processing and transmission. JotForm Inc. is certified as a PCI DSS Level 1 Compliant Service Provider, the highest security attainment you can have as a business that collects payments from, and integrates with, credit cards. We perform annual audits to ensure our handling of your credit card information aligns with industry guidelines. [Read more here](https://www.jotform.com/blog/314-JotForm-is-Now-PCI-DSS-Service-Provider-Level-I-Compliant).

**Account settings.**  You can set various preferences and personal details on pages, such as your [account settings page](https://www.jotform.com/myaccount/). For example, your default language, timezone and communication preferences (e.g. opting in or out of receiving marketing emails from JotForm Inc.).

**Form data.**  We store your form data (questions and responses) for you.

**Other data you intentionally share.**  We may collect your personal information or data if you submit it to us in other contexts. For example, if you provide us with a testimonial, or participate in a JotForm Inc. contest.

**We don’t share or use your respondents’ email addresses.**  JotForm Inc. will not contact your form respondents or individuals in your Address Book except at your direction. JotForm Inc. will not sell or make available these email addresses to any third parties.

**Information JotForm Inc. collects about you indirectly or passively when you interact with us.**

**Usage data.**  JotForm Inc. collects usage data about you whenever you interact with our services. This may include which web pages you visit, what you click on, when you performed those actions, and so on. Additionally, like most websites today, our web servers keep log files that record data each time a device accesses those servers. The log files contain data about the nature of each access, including originating IP addresses, internet service providers, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system versions, and timestamps.

**Device data.**  JotForm Inc. collects data from the device and application you use to access our services, such as your IP address, operating system version, device type, system and performance information, and browser type. We may also infer your geographic location based on your IP address.

**Referral data.**  If you arrive at a JotForm Inc. website from an external source (such as a link on another website or in an email), JotForm Inc. records information about the source that referred you to us.

**Information from third parties.**  JotForm Inc. may collect your personal information or data from third parties, if you have given permission to those third parties to share your information.

**Information from page tags.**  JotForm Inc. uses third party tracking services that employ cookies and page tags (also known as [web beacons](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug)) to collect aggregated and anonymized data about visitors to our websites. This data includes usage and user statistics. Emails sent by JotForm Inc. or by users through our services may include page tags that allow the sender to collect information about who opened those emails and clicked on links in them. We do this to allow the email sender to measure the performance of their email messaging and to learn how to improve email deliverability and open rates.

**Information from page tags.**  JotForm Inc. uses third party tracking services that employ cookies and page tags (also known as [web beacons](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug)) to collect aggregated and anonymized data about visitors to our websites. This data includes usage and user statistics. Emails sent by JotForm Inc. or by users through our services may include page tags that allow the sender to collect information about who opened those emails and clicked on links in them. We do this to allow the email sender to measure the performance of their email messaging and to learn how to improve email deliverability and open rates.

**How does  JotForm Inc. use the information we collect?**

JotForm Inc. treats your form questions and responses as information that is private to you, unless you have made your form questions and responses available via a public link. JotForm Inc. knows that, in many cases, you want to keep your form questions and responses (which we collectively refer to as “form data”) private. Unless you decide to share your form questions and/or responses with the public, such as by making the form questions and responses available via a public link, JotForm Inc. does not use your form data other than as described in this privacy policy, or unless we have your consent. We do not sell or make available your form data to third parties without your permission.

Generally, JotForm Inc. uses the information collected in connection with providing our services to you and, on your behalf, to your form respondents. For example, specific ways JotForm Inc. uses this information are listed below. See the next section of this privacy policy to understand how your information is shared. However, this privacy policy is not intended to restrict our use of form questions or responses that you have chosen to make available online through a public link. **To provide you with our services.**

This includes providing you with customer support, which requires JotForm Inc. to access your information to assist you, such as with form design and creation or technical troubleshooting.

Certain features of our services use the content of your form questions and responses and your account information in additional ways. Feature descriptions will clearly identify where this is the case. You can avoid the use of your form data in this way by simply choosing not to use such features. For example, by using our form templates feature, to add questions to your forms, you also permit us to aggregate the responses you receive to those questions with responses received by other form templates users who have used the same questions. We may then report statistics about the aggregated (and de-identified) data sent to you and other form creators.

If you choose to link your JotForm Inc. account with a third party account, such as your Google or Facebook account, JotForm Inc. may use the information you allow us to collect from those third parties to provide you with additional features, services, and personalized content.

In order to provide you with useful options to use the services together with social media and other applications, JotForm Inc. may give you the option to export information to, and collect information from, third party applications and websites, including platforms such as Google and Twitter and social networking sites such as Facebook. When exporting and collecting such information, you may be disclosing your information to the individuals or organizations responsible for operating and maintaining such third party applications and sites, and your information may be accessible by others visiting or using those applications or sites. We do not own or operate the applications or websites that you connect with, and you should review the privacy policies and statements of such websites to ensure you are comfortable with the ways in which they use the information you share with them.

**To manage our services.**  JotForm Inc. internally uses your information, including certain form data, for the following limited purposes:

**To monitor, maintain, and improve our services and features.**  JotForm Inc. internally performs statistical and other analysis on information we collect, including usage data, device data, referral data, question and response data and information from page tags, to analyze and measure user behavior and trends, to understand how people use our services, and to monitor, troubleshoot and improve our services, including to help us evaluate or devise new features. JotForm Inc. may use your information for internal purposes designed to keep our services secure and operational, such as for troubleshooting and testing purposes, and for service improvement, marketing, research and development purposes.

**To enforce our Terms of Use.**

**To prevent potentially illegal activities.**

**To screen for and prevent undesirable or abusive activity.**  For example, JotForm Inc. has automated systems that screen content for activities such as, phishing, spam, and fraud.

**To create new services, features or content.**  JotForm Inc. may use your form data and form metadata (that is, data about the characteristics of a form) for our internal purposes to create and provide new services, features or content. Regarding form metadata, JotForm Inc. may look at statistics like response rates, question and answer word counts, and the average number of questions in a form and publish interesting observations about these for informational or marketing purposes. When JotForm Inc. does this, neither individual form creators nor form respondents will be identified or identifiable unless we have obtained their permission.

**To facilitate account creation and the logon process.**  If you choose to link your JotForm Inc. account to a third party account, such as your Google or Facebook account, we use the information you allowed JotForm Inc. to collect from those third parties to facilitate the account creation and login process.

**To contact you about your service or account.**  JotForm Inc. occasionally sends you communications of a transactional nature (e.g. service-related announcements, billing-related matters, changes to our services or policies, a welcome email when you first register). You are prevented from opt out of this type of communication since it is required to provide our services to you.

**To contact you for marketing purposes.**  JotForm Inc. will send you promotional emails only if you have consented to our contacting you for this purpose. For example, during the account registration process, JotForm Inc. will ask for your permission to use your information to contact you for promotional purposes. You may opt out of these communications at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in them, or changing the relevant setting on your [My Account](https://www.jotform.com/myaccount/) page.

**To respond to legal requests and prevent harm.**  If JotForm Inc. receives a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data held to determine the appropriate response.

**With whom do we share or disclose your information?**

JotForm Inc. does not sell or make available your form data without your express permission,

When might JotForm Inc. disclose your form data to third parties? Only for a limited number of reasons. JotForm Inc. not holds your information with our service providers who help us to provide our services to you. JotForm Inc. has contracts with these service providers to keep your information confidential and to use it only for the purpose of providing their services. For example, JotForm Inc. uses payment processors who help us to process credit card transactions. By using our services, you authorize JotForm Inc. to sub-contract in this manner on your behalf.In rare circumstances, we may share information if required by law, or in a corporate restructuring or acquisition context (see below for more details).

**Sharing your forms with the public.**

You are able to control who can take your form by changing your collector settings. For example, forms can be made completely public, and indexable by search engines. You can also choose to share your form responses instantly or at a public location.

JotForm Inc. recognizes that you have entrusted us with safeguarding the privacy of your information. Because that trust is very important to us, the only time JotForm Inc. will disclose or share your personal information or form data with a third party is when JotForm Inc. has done one of three things, in accordance with applicable law: (a) given you notice, such as in this privacy policy; (b) obtained your express consent, such as through an opt-in checkbox; or (c) de-identified or aggregated the information so that individuals or other entities cannot reasonably be identified by it. Where required by law, JotForm Inc. will obtain your express consent prior to disclosing or sharing any personal information.

We may disclose:

**Your information to our service providers.**  JotForm Inc. uses service providers who help us to provide you with our services. JotForm Inc. gives relevant persons working for some of these providers access to your information, but only to the extent necessary for them to perform their services for us. JotForm Inc. also implements reasonable contractual and technical protections to ensure the confidentiality of your personal information and data is maintained, used only for the provision of their services to us, and handled in accordance with this privacy policy. Examples of service providers include payment processors, hosting services, email service providers, and web traffic analytics tools.

**Your account details to your billing contact.**  If your account holder details are different from the billing contact listed for your account, JotForm Inc. may disclose your identity and account details to the billing contact upon their request. JotForm Inc. also will usually attempt to notify you of such requests. By using our services and agreeing to this privacy policy, you consent to this disclosure.

**Your email address to your organization.**  If the email address under which you’ve registered your account belongs to or is controlled by an organization, JotForm Inc. may disclose that email address to that organization in order to help it understand who associated with that organization uses JotForm Inc., and to assist the organization with its enterprise accounts. You are advised not to use a work email address for JotForm Inc. services unless you are authorized to do so, and are therefore comfortable with this disclosure.

**Aggregated or de-identified (anonymized) information to third parties to improve or promote JotForm Inc. services.**  No individuals can reasonably be identified or linked to any part of the information we share with third parties to improve or promote JotForm Inc. services.

**The presence of a cookie to advertise JotForm Inc. services.**  JotForm Inc. may ask advertising networks and exchanges to display ads promoting our services on other websites. JotForm Inc. may ask these networks to deliver those ads based on the presence of a cookie, but in doing so will not share any other personal information with the advertiser. Our advertising network partners may use cookies and page tags or web beacons to collect certain non-personal information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you with targeted advertising based upon your interests.

**Your information if required or permitted by law.**  JotForm Inc. may disclose your information as required or permitted by law, or when JotForm Inc. believes that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, subpoena, or other legal process served on us.

**Your information if there’s a change in business ownership or structure.**  If ownership of all or substantially all of JotForm Inc. business changes, or JotForm Inc. undertakes a corporate reorganization, including a merger, acquisition or consolidation or any other action or transfer between JotForm Inc. entities, you expressly consent to JotForm Inc. transferring your information to the new owner or successor entity so that we can continue providing our services. If required, JotForm Inc. will notify the applicable data protection agency in each jurisdiction of such a transfer in accordance with the notification procedures under applicable data protection laws.

**Information you expressly consent to be shared.**  For example, JotForm Inc. may expressly request your permission to provide your contact details to third parties for various purposes, including to allow those third parties to contact you for marketing purposes. You may later revoke your permission, but if you wish to stop receiving communications from a third party to which we provided your information with your permission, you will need to contact that third party directly.

**What are your rights to your information?**

**Update your account details.**  You can update your registration and other account information on your [My Account](https://www.jotform.com/myaccount/) page. Information is updated immediately.

**Access and correct your personal information.  **As an account holder, you may access and correct certain personal information that JotForm Inc. holds about you by visiting your My Account page. Some account holders and other individuals have certain legal rights to obtain information of whether we hold personal information about them, to access personal information we hold about them, and to obtain its correction, update, amendment or deletion in appropriate circumstances. For some information, these rights may be exercised through the My Account page mentioned above, and in all cases, requests to exercise these rights may be directed to our [customer support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/) team. These rights are subject to some exceptions, such as where giving you access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals. JotForm Inc. will respond to your request to exercise these rights within a reasonable time and, where required by law or where we deem it otherwise appropriate and practicable to do so, we will honor your request.

**Download/backup your form data.**  Depending on what subscription plan you have, JotForm Inc. provides you with the ability to export, share and publish your form data in a variety of formats. This allows you to create your own backups or conduct offline data analysis.

**Delete your form data.**  Deleting form data will not permanently delete form data immediately. As long as you maintain an account with JotForm Inc., we may retain your deleted data for a limited time but no longer than 30 days in the event you accidentally delete data and need to restore it (which you can request by contacting [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/)). To the extent permitted by law, JotForm Inc. will permanently delete your data if you request to cancel your account. However, if your data was previously made available to the public through a public link, additional copies of your data may exist on an external website even after your account has been deleted.

**Cancel your account.**  To cancel and delete your account, please contact [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/). Deleting your account will cause all the form data in the account to be permanently deleted from our systems within a reasonable time period, as permitted by law, and will disable your access to any other services that require a JotForm Inc. account. JotForm Inc. will respond to any such request, and any appropriate request to access, correct, update or delete your personal information within the time period specified by law, if applicable, or without excessive delay. JotForm Inc. will promptly fulfill requests to delete personal data unless the request is not technically feasible or such data is required to be retained by law, in which case JotForm Inc. will block access to such data, if required by law.

**For how long does JotForm Inc. retain your data?**  We generally retain your data for as long as you have an account with JotForm Inc., or to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. Data that is deleted from our servers may remain as residual copies on offsite backup media for up to approximately one month afterward.

**Form data deleted from within the account**

You can delete forms and data from within your account at any time. Form data that you delete from your account will be rendered inaccessible, but not permanently deleted, as permitted by law. JotForm Inc. retains your data to allow you to restore data that has been deleted accidentally.

JotForm Inc. will eventually permanently purge old, deleted data to reclaim storage space, so it cannot be guaranteed that JotForm Inc. will be able to restore deleted data. The more recent the deletion, the more likely it will be able to be restored. Once deleted from your account, the data will be fully purged from our system within 30 days.

JotForm Inc. generally does not use deleted form data for any purpose other than to give you the opportunity to restore it. Sometimes JotForm Inc. may retain deleted data to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. In these cases, JotForm Inc. ensures that access to such data is blocked except for the purposes for which JotForm Inc. has been required to retain the information.

**Account deleted from within the account**

You can request to delete your account and form data associated with it at any time. After you initiate the deletion of your account, the account is disabled immediately, but the account and form data will be held in our database for 30 days until our next regularly scheduled deletion cycle, at which point it will be permanently deleted. You can contact JotForm Inc. within that time frame to request the account be restored. After the account is permanently deleted, JotForm Inc. won’t be able to restore it or the form data it contained.

**User account in a team deleted by an Administrator**

The Primary Admin or Admin of a team can delete a user account from a team at any time. This disables the user account immediately, but its form data will be held in a JotForm Inc. database for 30 days before being deleted. The Primary Admin can contact JotForm Inc. within this 30-day time frame to request the account be restored.

**Security, cookies and other important information**

**Changes to this privacy policy.**

JotForm Inc. may modify this privacy policy at any time. JotForm Inc. will notify you by publishing the changes on this website. If JotForm Inc. determines the changes are material, you will be provided with additional, prominent notice as is appropriate under the circumstances, such as via email or in another conspicuous manner reasonably designed to notify you. If, after being informed of these changes, you do not cancel your subscription and continue to use JotForm Inc. services beyond the advance-notice period, you will be considered as having expressly consented to the changes in the privacy policy. If you disagree with the terms of this privacy policy or any updated privacy policy, you may close your account at any time. **Security.**  Details about JotForm Inc.’s security practices are available through our [Security Statement](https://www.jotform.com/security/). JotForm Inc. is committed to handling your personal information and data with integrity and care. However, regardless of the security protections and precautions undertaken, there is always a risk that your personal data may be viewed and used by unauthorized third parties as a result of collecting and transmitting your data through the Internet. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, contact [customer support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/).

**Data locations.**  JotForm Inc. servers are based in the United States, so your personal information will be hosted and processed by JotForm Inc. in the United States. Your personal information may also be processed in, or transferred or disclosed to, countries in which JotForm Inc. offices are located and in which our service providers are located or have servers.

**Cookie Notification.**  JotForm Inc. and our partners use cookies and similar technologies on our websites. Cookies are small bits of data we store on the device you use to access our services so JotForm Inc. can recognize repeat users. Each cookie expires after a certain period of time, depending on what we use it for. JotForm Inc. uses cookies and similar technologies for several reasons:

**To make the JotForm Inc. website easier to use.**  If you use the “Remember me” feature when you sign into your account, JotForm Inc. may store your username in a cookie to make it quicker for you to sign in whenever you return to JotForm Inc.

**For security reasons.**  JotForm Inc. uses cookies to authenticate your identity, such as confirming whether you are currently logged into JotForm Inc..

**To provide you with personalized content.**  JotForm Inc. may store user preferences, such as your default language, in cookies to personalize the content you see. JotForm Inc. also uses cookies to ensure that users can’t retake certain forms that they have already completed.

**To improve our services.**  JotForm Inc. uses cookies to measure your usage of our websites and track referral data, as well as to occasionally display different versions of content to you. This information helps JotForm Inc. develop and improve our services and optimize the content JotForm Inc. displays to users.

**To advertise to you.**  JotForm Inc., or our service providers and other third parties we work with, may place cookies when you visit our website and other websites or when you open emails that are sent to you, in order to provide you with more tailored marketing content (about our services or other services), and to evaluate whether this content is useful or effective. For instance, JotForm Inc. may evaluate which advertisements are clicked on most often, and whether those clicks lead users to make better use of our tools, features and services. If you don’t want to receive advertisements that are tailored to you based on your anonymous online activity, you may “opt out” of many of the companies that are involved in such tailoring by going to [https://www.aboutads.info](https://www.aboutads.info/). Opting out in this way does not mean you will not receive any advertisements; it just means that you will not receive advertisements from such companies that have been tailored to you based on your activities and inferred preferences.

**Google Analytics.**  In addition to the above, JotForm Inc. has implemented on our websites and other services certain Google Analytics features that support Display Advertising, including re-targeting. Visitors to our websites may opt out of certain types of Google Analytics tracking, customize the Google Display Network ads by using the [Google Ad Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/) and learn more about how Google serves advertisements by viewing its [Customer Ads Help Center](https://support.google.com/ads/?hl=en). If you do not wish to participate in Google Analytics, you may also download the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

JotForm Inc. doesn’t believe cookies are sinister, but you can still choose to remove or disable cookies via your browser. Refer to your web browser’s configuration documentation to learn how to do this. Please note that doing this may adversely impact your ability to use our services. Enabling cookies ensures a smoother experience when using our websites. To manage flash cookies, [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). By using our websites and agreeing to this privacy policy, you expressly consent to the use of cookies as described in this policy.

**Blogs and Forums.**  JotForm Inc. websites may offer publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. JotForm Inc. is not responsible for any personal information you choose to submit in these areas of our site. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/). In some cases, JotForm Inc. may not be able to fulfill your request and an explanation will be provided. Commenting systems on our blogs are managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. Please review that application’s privacy policy to learn how the third party uses your information.

**Online Tracking.**  JotForm Inc. currently do not process or comply with any web browser’s “do not track” signal or other similar mechanism that indicates a request to disable online tracking of individual users who visit our websites or use our services, unless otherwise stated in a service-specific privacy statement.

**Social Media Features.**  JotForm Inc. websites may include social media features or widgets, such as the Facebook Like button. Use of these features may allow them to collect your IP address, detect which page you are visiting on our site, and set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing it.

**Safety of Children and COPPA.**  JotForm Inc. services are not intended for and may not permissibly be used by individuals under the age of 13. JotForm Inc. does not knowingly collect personal data from persons under 13 or allow them to register. If it comes to our attention that JotForm Inc. has collected personal data from such a person, JotForm Inc. may delete this information without notice. If you have reason to believe that this has occurred, please contact [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/).

**English version controls.**  Non-English translations of this privacy policy are provided for convenience. In the event of any ambiguity or conflict between translations, the English version is authoritative.

**Additional information for European Union users**

**Personal data**

For users located in the EU, references to “personal information” in this policy are equivalent to what is commonly referred to as “personal data” in the EU.

  * **About IP addresses.**  JotForm Inc. servers record the incoming IP addresses of visitors to our websites, whether or not the visitor has a JotForm Inc. account and store the IP addresses in log files. JotForm Inc. uses these log files for purposes such as system administration and maintenance, record keeping, tracking referring web sites, inferring your location, and security purposes (e.g. controlling abuse, spam and DDOS attacks). JotForm Inc. also stores IP addresses along with certain actions you take on our system. IP addresses are only linked to form responses if a form creator has configured a form to collect IP addresses. By agreeing to this privacy policy, you expressly consent to JotForm Inc. using your IP address for the foregoing purposes. If you wish to opt out from the foregoing consent to use your IP address, you must cancel your account (if you have one) or not respond to a form if requested to do so.
  *  **Data controller.**  JotForm Inc., whose contact information is listed above, is the data controller for registration, billing and other account information that we collect from users in the EU. However, the data controller for form data is the form creator. The form creator determines how their form questions and responses are used and disclosed. JotForm Inc. only processes such form data in accordance with the instructions and permissions (including those given under this privacy policy) selected by the form creator when they create and administer their form.
  *  **Accessing and correcting your personal data.**  You have the right to access and correct the personal information that JotForm Inc. holds about you. This right may be exercised by visiting your account’s [My Account](https://www.jotform.com/myaccount/) page or by contacting [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/).
  *  **Your responsibilities.**  By using JotForm Inc. services, you agree to comply with adequate data protection requirements when collecting and using your form data, such as requirements to inform respondents about the specific uses and disclosures of their data.

**Consents. By clicking “I Agree” or any other button indicating your acceptance of this privacy policy, you expressly consent to the following:**

  * You consent to the collection, use, disclosure and processing of your personal data in the manner described in this privacy policy, including our procedures relating to cookies, IP addresses and log files.
  * JotForm Inc. servers are based in the United States, so your personal data will be primarily processed by JotForm Inc. in the United States. You consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States by JotForm Inc. and in the data locations identified in Section 5 by our various affiliates and service providers.
  * You consent and agree that JotForm Inc. may transfer your data to data processors located in countries, including the United States, which do not have data protection laws that provide the same level of protection that exists in countries in the European Economic Area. Your consent is voluntary, and you may revoke your consent by opting out at any time. Please note that if you opt-out, we may no longer be able to provide you our services.
  * You consent to JotForm Inc. sharing your personal data with relevant persons working for service providers who assist us to provide our services.
  * If you have enabled cookies on your web browser, you consent to our use of cookies as described in this privacy policy.

**PRIVACY FOR FORM RESPONDENTS**

  * **What information does JotForm Inc. collect?**

When you respond to forms hosted by JotForm Inc., we collect, on behalf and upon instructions, including the ones provided in this privacy policy, of form creators, information relating to you and your use of our services from a variety of sources. These are listed below. The sections afterward describe what JotForm Inc. does with this information.

**Information JotForm Inc. collects directly from you.**

  * **Form responses.**  JotForm Inc. collects and stores the form responses that you submit. The form creator is responsible for this data and manages it. A form may ask you to provide personal information or data. If you have any questions about a form you are taking, please contact the form creator directly as JotForm Inc. is not responsible for the content of that form. The form creator is usually the same person that invited you to take the form and sometimes they have their own privacy policy.

**Are your form responses anonymous?**

You will need to ask the form creator as it depends how the individual, company or organization has chosen to configure the form(s). JotForm Inc. provides instructions describing how a form creator can ensure collected responses are done so anonymously. However, even if a form creator has followed those steps, specific questions in the form may still ask you for your personal information or data that could be used to identify you.

**Information JotForm Inc. collects about you from other sources.**

  * **Usage data.**  JotForm Inc. collects usage data about you whenever you interact with our services. This may include which web pages you visit, what you click on, when you performed those actions, and so on. Additionally, as with most websites today, JotForm Inc. web servers keep log files that record data each time a device accesses those servers. The log files contain data about the nature of each access, including originating IP addresses, internet service providers, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system versions, and timestamps. Note that JotForm Inc. does not link this usage data to your form responses.
  *  **Device data.**  JotForm Inc. collects data from the device and application you use to access our services, such as your IP address, operating system version, device type, system and performance information, and browser type. JotForm Inc. may also infer your geographic location based on your IP address. Your IP address will be linked to your form responses unless a form creator has disabled IP address collection for the form you respond to.
  *  **Referral data.**  JotForm Inc. records information about the source that referred you to a form (e.g. a link on a website or in an email).
  *  **Information from page tags.**  JotForm Inc. uses third party tracking services that employ cookies and page tags (also known as [web beacons](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug)) to collect aggregated and anonymized data about visitors to our websites. This data includes usage and user statistics.
  *  **Your email address.**  If a form creator uses an email field to send you a form invitation email, JotForm Inc. collects your email address when the form creator provides it to us. JotForm Inc. does not use this to send you email except at the direction of a form creator. The emails JotForm Inc. sends on behalf of a form creator appear to come from that form creator’s email address. If you no longer want to be contacted by a form creator, please contact the form creator directly.

**Providing form responses is voluntary.**

Remember, you can always choose not to provide an answer to any given form question (especially those requesting your personal information or data). However, sometimes this will prevent you from completing a form if the form creator has marked that question as requiring an answer.

  1. **How does JotForm Inc. use the information collected?**

Your form responses are owned and managed by the form creator, and JotForm Inc. treats that information as private to the form creator, except if the form creator has made the questions and responses available via a public link. Please contact the form creator directly to understand how the individual, company or organization uses your form responses. Some form creators may provide you with a privacy policy or notice at the time you complete its form and we encourage you to review that to understand how the form creator will handle your responses. **.**  JotForm Inc. does not sell or make available form responses to third parties without the form creator’s permission and JotForm Inc. does not use any contact details collected in our customers’ forms to contact form respondents.

JotForm Inc. also uses the information collected from you, including usage data, device data, referral data and information from page tags to manage and improve our services, for research purposes, and for the various purposes described in the this privacy policy.

  1. **With whom does JotForm Inc. share or disclose your information?**

JotForm Inc. does not sell or make available your form responses without express permission! JotForm Inc. will share your form responses with third parties only as described in this privacy policy.

**JotForm Inc. discloses:**

**Your form responses to form creators.**

JotForm Inc hosts forms created by form creators. However, form creators are actually the primary curator of form data. Anything you expressly disclose in your form responses will, naturally, be provided to them. Please contact the form creator directly to understand how they might share your form responses. Please see this privacy policy to understand what JotForm Inc. tells form creators about how JotForm Inc. handles form responses, and to whom JotForm Inc. may disclose form responses.

**What are your rights to your information?**

**Contact the form creator to access and correct your responses and personal information.**  Because JotForm Inc. collects form responses on behalf of form creators, you will need to contact the form creator if you have any questions about the form, or if you want to access, update, or delete anything in your responses. JotForm Inc. provides form creators with tools to maintain the responses they collect through their forms. You may request access to and correction of the personal information we hold about you by contacting customer support, however in most cases JotForm Inc. cannot provide you with this access since form responses are the form creator’s private information (except if the form creator has made the questions and responses available via a public link) and giving you access may have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals. JotForm Inc. will respond to your request for access or correction within a reasonable time and, where reasonable and practicable to do so, JotForm Inc. will provide access to your personal information in the manner requested by you.

**Contact the form creator to access and correct your responses and personal information.**  Because JotForm Inc. collects form responses on behalf of form creators, you will need to contact the form creator if you have any questions about the form, or if you want to access, update, or delete anything in your responses. JotForm Inc. provides form creators with tools to maintain the responses they collect through their forms. You may request access to and correction of the personal information we hold about you by contacting customer support, however in most cases JotForm Inc. cannot provide you with this access since form responses are the form creator’s private information (except if the form creator has made the questions and responses available via a public link) and giving you access may have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals. JotForm Inc. will respond to your request for access or correction within a reasonable time and, where reasonable and practicable to do so, JotForm Inc. will provide access to your personal information in the manner requested by you.

**Opt out of receiving forms.**  You may opt out of receiving email invitations to complete forms which are sent by form creators via JotForm Inc.

**Security, cookies and other important information**

Changes to this privacy policy. JotForm Inc. may modify this privacy policy at any time and you will be notified by publishing the changes on this website. If JotForm Inc. determines the changes are material, you will be provided with additional, prominent notice as is appropriate under the circumstances, such as via email or in another conspicuous manner reasonably designed to notify you.If, after being informed of the changes, you continue to use our services beyond the advance-notice period, you will be considered as having expressly consented to the changes in our privacy policy. If you disagree with the terms of this privacy policy or any updated privacy policy, you may close your account, if you have one, at any time or not respond to a form. **Security.**  Details about JotForm Inc ’s security practices are available through our [Security Statement](https://www.jotform.com/security/). JotForm Inc. is committed to handling your personal information and data with integrity and care. However, regardless of the security protections and precautions JotForm Inc. undertakes, there is always a risk that your personal data may be viewed and used by unauthorized third parties as a result of collecting and transmitting your data through the Internet. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, contact [customer support.](https://www.jotform.com/answers/)

**Data locations.**  JotForm Inc. servers are based in the United States, so your personal information will be hosted and processed by us in the United States. Your personal information may also be processed in, or transferred or disclosed to, countries in which JotForm Inc. offices are located and in which our service providers are located or have services.

**Cookie Notification.**  JotForm Inc. and our partners use cookies and similar technologies on our websites. Cookies are small bits of data we store on the device you use to access our services so we can recognize repeat users. Each cookie expires after a certain period of time, depending on what we use it for. JotForm Inc. uses cookies and similar technologies for several reasons:

**To make our site easier to use.**  If you use the “Remember me” feature when you sign into your account, JotForm Inc. may store your username in a cookie to make it quicker for you to sign in whenever you return to JotForm Inc..

**For security reasons.**  JotForm Inc. uses cookies to authenticate your identity, such as confirming whether you are currently logged into JotForm Inc..

**To provide you with personalized content.**  JotForm Inc. may store user preferences, such as your default language, in cookies to personalize the content you see. JotForm Inc. also uses cookies to ensure that users can’t retake certain forms that they have already completed.

**To improve our services.**  JotForm Inc. uses cookies to measure your usage of our websites and track referral data, as well as to occasionally display different versions of content to you. This information helps us to develop and improve our services and optimize the content we display to users.

**To advertise to you.**  JotForm Inc., or our service providers and other third parties we work with, may place cookies when you visit our website and other websites or when you open emails that are sent to you, in order to provide you with more tailored marketing content (about our services or other services), and to evaluate whether this content is useful or effective. For instance, JotForm Inc. may evaluate which advertisements are clicked on most often, and whether those clicks lead users to make better use of our tools, features and services. If you don’t want to receive advertisements that are tailored to you based on your anonymous online activity, you may “opt out” of many of the companies that are involved in such tailoring by going to [https://www.aboutads.info](https://www.aboutads.info/). Opting out in this way does not mean you will not receive any advertisements; it just means that you will not receive advertisements from such companies that have been tailored to you based on your activities and inferred preferences.

**Google Analytics.**  In addition to the above, JotForm Inc. has implemented on our websites and other services certain Google Analytics features that support Display Advertising, including re-targeting. Visitors to our websites may opt out of certain types of Google Analytics tracking, customize the Google Display Network ads by using the [Google Ad Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/) and learn more about how Google serves ads by viewing its [Customer Ads Help Center](https://support.google.com/ads/?hl=en). If you do not wish to participate in Google Analytics, you may also download the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

JotForm Inc. does not believe cookies are sinister, but you can still choose to remove or disable cookies via your browser. Refer to your web browser’s configuration documentation to learn how to do this. Please note that doing this may adversely impact your ability to use our services. Enabling cookies ensures a smoother experience when using JotForm Inc. websites. To manage flash cookies, [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). By using JotForm Inc. websites and agreeing to this privacy policy, you expressly consent to the use of cookies as described in this policy.

**Blogs and Forums.**  JotForm Inc. websites may offer publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. We’re not responsible for any personal information you choose to submit in these areas of our site. Be aware that any personal information you provide may be used for illegal activity. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/). In some cases, we may not be able to fulfill your request and we will let you know why. Commenting systems on our blogs are managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. Please review that application’s privacy policy to learn how the third party uses your information.

**Online Tracking.**  JotForm Inc. currently does not process or comply with any web browser’s “do not track” signal or other similar mechanism that indicates a request to disable online tracking of individual users who visit our websites or use our services (unless otherwise stated in a service-specific privacy statement).

**Social Media Features.**  JotForm Inc. websites may include social media features or widgets, such as the Facebook Like button. Use of these features may allow them to collect your IP address, detect which page you are visiting on our site, and set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing it.

**Safety of Minors and COPPA.**  JotForm Inc. services are not intended for and may not be used by minors. “Minors” are individuals under the age of majority in their place of residence (or under 13 in the United States). JotForm Inc. does not knowingly collect personal data from minors or allow them to register. If it comes to our attention that we have collected personal data from a minor, JotForm Inc. may delete this information without notice. If you have reason to believe that this has occurred, please contact [Customer Support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/).

**English version controls.**  Non-English translations of this privacy policy are provided for convenience. In the event of any ambiguity or conflict between translations, the English version is authoritative.

**Additional information for European Union users** **“Personal data”.**  For users located in the EU, references to “personal information” in this policy are equivalent to what is commonly referred to as “personal data” in the EU.

**About IP addresses.**  JotForm Inc. servers record the incoming IP addresses of visitors to JotForm Inc. websites, whether or not the visitor has a JotForm Inc. account, and store the IP addresses in log files. JotForm Inc. uses these log files for purposes such as system administration and maintenance, record keeping, tracking referring web sites, inferring your location, and security purposes (e.g. controlling abuse, spam and DDOS attacks). JotForm Inc. also stores IP addresses along with certain actions you take on our system. IP addresses are only linked to form responses if a form creator has configured a form to collect IP addresses. By agreeing to this privacy policy, you expressly consent to JotForm Inc. using your IP address for the foregoing purposes. If you wish to opt out from the foregoing consent to use your IP address, you must cancel your account (if you have one) or not respond to a form if requested to do so.

**Data controller.**  JotForm Inc., whose contact information is listed above, is the data controller for registration, billing and other account information that we collect from users in the EU. However, the data controller for form data is the form creator. The form creator determines how their form questions and responses are used and disclosed. JotForm Inc. only processes such form data in accordance with the instructions and permissions (including those given under this privacy policy) selected by the form creator when they create and administer their form.

**Accessing and correcting your personal data.**  You have the right to access and correct the personal information that JotForm Inc. holds about you. This right may be exercised by contacting [customer support](https://www.jotform.com/answers/).

**Consents**

By clicking “I Agree” or any other button indicating your acceptance of this privacy policy, you expressly consent to the following:You consent to the collection, use, disclosure and processing of your personal data in the manner described in this privacy policy, including our procedures relating to  **cookies, IP addresses and log files**.

JotForm Inc. servers are based in the United States, so your personal data will be primarily processed in the United States. You consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States by JotForm Inc.. and in the data locations identified in Section 5 by our various affiliates and service providers.

You consent and agree that JotForm Inc. may transfer your data to data processors located in countries, including the United States, which do not have data protection laws that provide the same level of protection that exists in countries in the European Economic Area. Your consent is voluntary, and you may revoke your consent by opting out at any time. Please note that if you opt-out, we may no longer be able to provide you our services.

You consent to JotForm Inc. sharing your personal data with relevant persons working for service providers who assist us to provide our services.

If you have enabled cookies on your web browser, you consent to JotForm Inc. use of cookies as described in this privacy policy.

**Privacy Shield (relevant to our EU users)** JotForm Inc. is located in the United States and accordingly, data (to include Respondent data) will be transferred to the United States.

JotForm Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield. JotForm Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal information and data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.  **https://www.privacyshield.gov/**.

JotForm Inc. also complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

When JotForm Inc. receives personal information under the Privacy Shield and then transfers it to a third-party service provider acting as agent on JotForm Inc.’s behalf, JotForm Inc. has certain liability under the Privacy Shield if both (i) the agent processes the information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield and (ii) JotForm Inc. is responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, JotForm Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, JotForm Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Please contact JotForm Inc. as described in Section 14 below if you have any concerns or complaints of any nature. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider, (free of charge) at https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Questions**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please feel free to [contact us](https://www.jotform.com/contact/).
